Guide to the Jean Toomer Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1920-54; Series II; 20.5; (49 boxes)
  - ESSAYS AND LECTURES
    - Literature
      - "Negro Psychology in the Emperor Jones": typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 999)
      - "A Note on the Introduction by W. M.": typescripts, 1920 (Box 48, Folder 1000)
      - "Notes at a Turn": drafts, 1923-24 (Box 48, Folder 1001)
      - "Notes for a Novel": drafts, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1002)
      - "Open Letter to Gorham B. Munson": printed in S4N, issue 35, 1923 Mar-Apr (Box 48, Folder 1003)
      - "Oxen Cart and Warfare": printed in The Little Review, 1924-25 (Box 48, Folder 1004)
      - "Poetry and Spiritual Rebirth": outlines, 1947 Apr 15 (Box 48, Folder 1005)
      - "Portrait of an Inner Relationship between AE and the Self behind Me": holograph & fragments, 1937 May (Box 48, Folder 1006)
      - "The Psychology and Craft of Writing": notes, drafts, publicity, 1930 May-Jun (Box 48, Folder 1007)
      - "The South in Literature": typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1008)
      - "Whitman and the Use of Current Idiom": typescript (Box 48, Folder 1009)
      - Unidentified: draft fragments and publicity, 1930, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1010)
    - New Mexico
      - "New Mexico after India": notes and drafts (Box 48, Folder 1011)
      - "Noises at Night": typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1012)
      - "Sequences": notes and drafts (Box 48, Folder 1013)
      - Unidentified: typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1014)
    - Psychology and religion
      - "Alertness": notes, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1015)
      - "America 1924": typescript (Box 48, Folder 1016)
      - "Associations on Religion": typescript, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1017)
      - "Awareness, Consciousness, Conditioned and Unconditional Knowledge": notes (Box 48, Folder 1018)
      - "Becoming Behavior": notes, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1019)
      - "Beliefs and Assumptions": typescript (Box 49, Folder 1020)
      - "The Blessed Trinity": typescript, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1021)
      - "The Care Group": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1022)
      - "Change of View from External to Internal": holograph, 1936 [Sep] 22 (Box 49, Folder 1023)
      - "Creative Questions": holograph, 1938 May 22 (Box 49, Folder 1024)
      - "Creative Questions": typescripts, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1025)
      - "Desire, Doubt, Despair, Faith, and Aspiration": typescript (Box 49, Folder 1026)
      - "The Devil's Commandments": holograph (Box 49, Folder 1027)
      - "The Different Kinds of Philosophy": notes (Box 49, Folder 1028)
      - "The Double Religious Desires": outline, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1029)
      - "Easter": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1030)
      - "Energy": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1031)
      - "Environmental Thinking, Psychological Thinking": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1032)
      - "Exile, Come Home!"
        See: "The Blessed Trinity", Box 49, folder 1021
      - "Factor X": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1033)
      - "The Figure on the Wheel": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1034)
      - "Free Will": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1035)
      - "The Functions of Man to Woman": notes, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1036)
      - "God Help Me": notes, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1037)
      - "The God-Pointed Life": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1038)
      - "He Who Grows Thereby Serves God": typescript, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1039)
      - "Human Beings": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1040)
      - "I Do Not Know": typescript, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1041)
      - "I Pray the Lord": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1042)
      - "The Importance, the Primacy of Ideas": holograph, 1935 (Box 49, Folder 1043)
      - "An Increasing Sense that Something is Profoundly Wrong": holograph, 1937 Dec (Box 49, Folder 1044)
      - "The Individual and Democracy": typescript (Box 49, Folder 1045)
      - "Individualism: typescript of a prose poem" (Box 49, Folder 1046)
      - "Inner Action in Children": outline, 1937 May 30 (Box 49, Folder 1047)
      - "Largeness": drafts, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1048)
      - "Life's Centre": typescript, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1049)
      - "Lines Written in Response to Certain People Bowed Down by a Sense of Oppression...": drafts, 1939 Mar 15 (Box 49, Folder 1050)
      - "A Living Faith": typescript, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 1051)
      - "Love of People": outline, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1052)
      - "Meditation on Jung": holographs, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1053)
      - "Meditations": published in New Mexico Sentinel, 1937 Jul-Sep (Box 49, Folder 1054)
      - "Men are Made to Grow": outline, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1055)
      - "Men to Mend": outline (Box 49, Folder 1056)
      - "The Mind Formation": holograph, 1935 (Box 49, Folder 1057)
      - "Neutralizer-Attitude": drafts, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1058)
      - "A New Force for Cooperation": typescripts & printed version, 1934 Oct (Box 49, Folder 1059)
      - "Normal Man": typescript, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1060)
      - "Not In, Not Out": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1061)
      - "A Note on a Free Man": holograph, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1062)
      - "On Feeling": typescript, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1063)
      - "On Mal-forms and Unformed Experience": notes & typescripts (Box 49, Folder 1064)
      - "An Outline of Man": outline, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1065)
      - "People and Their Shells": holograph (Box 50, Folder 1066)
      - "A Philosophy for Artists": outline, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1067)
      - "The Pivotal Self": holographs, 1939 Jan-Feb (Box 50, Folder 1068)
      - "The Power": holographs, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1069)
      - "The Practice of the Presence of the True Self": outline & printed program, 1947 Mar 16 (Box 50, Folder 1070)
      - Prayers: holographs, 1939-46 (Box 50, Folder 1071)
      - "Prospectus of a Needed Profession": drafts, 1939 Nov-Dec (Box 50, Folder 1072)
      - "Psychiatry": holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1073)
      - "Psychology and Ourselves": outline and publicity, 1949-50 (Box 50, Folder 1074)
      - "Pupil of Myself": drafts, 1936 Dec 14 (Box 50, Folder 1075)
      - "Pure Pleasure": typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1076)
      - "Questions Asked by Biologists": notes & outline, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1077)
      - "Realizations of Ignorance & Innocence": holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1078)
      - "The Region of the Savior": holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1079)
      - "Religion": notes & typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1080)
      - "Religion in the War Age": holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1081)
      - "The Seed Remembers": outline, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1082)
      - Sermon: outline & program, 1949 May 29 (Box 50, Folder 1083)
      - Shrewness: drafts, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1084)
      - "Situation": holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1085)
      - "A Sketch of a Human Way": outline, 1939 May 5 (Box 50, Folder 1086)
      - "Standardized False Promises": typescript (Box 50, Folder 1087)
      - "The Struggle Is On": holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1088)
      - "The Things that Cause the Submergence of the Inner Life": holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1089)
      - "Three Psychological Classes": typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1090)
      - "Three Religious Types": outline, 1946 Jul 8 (Box 50, Folder 1091)
      - "To Dike": typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1092)
      - "Tools and a Mustard Seed": typescript, 1935 Jan 11 (Box 50, Folder 1093)
      - "Toomer Discloses Conclusions of Psychological Experiment Carmel Pine Cone, 1932 Mar 25 (Box 50, Folder 1094)
      - "The Trouble With Man": typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1095)
      - "The Two Rivers": holograph, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1096)
      - "Vitamen": notes, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1097)
      - "The Way of the Mystic": holograph, 1935 Nov 15 (Box 50, Folder 1098)
      - "We Still Have Hearts": typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1099)
      - "What Is Real": holographs, 1939 Feb 8-9 (Box 50, Folder 1100)
      - "Where Will We Look?": typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1101)
      - "Why": typescript, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1102)
      - "Work Ideas 1": page proofs & printed pamphlets (2 copies), 1937 Jan (Box 50, Folder 1103)
      - Unidentified: notes & holograph fragments, 1938-39, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1104)
      - Unidentified: typescript fragments, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1105)
    - Race Relations
      - "America & Problems": notes & drafts, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1106)
      - "The American Race": typescript, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1107)
      - "The Americans": notes & drafts, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1108)
      - "Brotherhood and Separation": outline (Box 51, Folder 1109)
      - "I Find It Queer": typescript (Box 51, Folder 1110)
      - "The Individual in America": notes (Box 51, Folder 1111)
      - "Mankind Means Brotherhood": typescript (Box 51, Folder 1112)
      - "Member of Man": holograph, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1113)
      - "The Negro Emergent": notes & drafts, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1114)
      - "A Preface to a Place and Function in Society": drafts, 1935 Mar-Apr (Box 51, Folder 1115-16)
      - "Prejudice": holograph, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1117)
      - "Race & Homogeneity": holograph, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1118)
      - "Race Problems and Modern Society": drafts (Box 51, Folder 1119-20)
      - "The Survival of Barbarisms": notes, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1121)
      - "Thus May It Be Said": typescript, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1122)
      - "What I Believe": typescript, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1123)
      - "World America": typescript, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1124)
      - Unidentified: draft fragments, 1935, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1125)
    - Social history
      - "The American Belief": notes & outline, 1943 Mar 15 (Box 51, Folder 1126)
      - "American Letter": typescript, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1127)
      - "Business": notes, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1128)
      - "Chicago": typescript, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1129)
      - George Washington: typescript, 1932 Nov 8 (Box 51, Folder 1130)
      - "The Human Crisis": typescripts, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1131)
      - "Is a Scott Radio the Radio for You?": typescripts, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1132)
      - "Opinions on the Questions of the Cahiers de l'Etoile": typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1133)
      - "Opinions on the Worlds Fair": typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1134)
      - "The Pebble Plan": holograph, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1135)
      - "Pests and Parasites": notes (Box 52, Folder 1136)
      - "A Possible Way to Peace?": holograph, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1137)
      - "Program for a Conscientious Citizen": typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1138)
      - "The Psychology of Protest": holograph, 1935 fall (Box 52, Folder 1139)
      - "Renunciation": holograph, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1140)
      - "Self-rule": outlines, 1943 Dec 15 (Box 52, Folder 1141)
      - "Selling": typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1142)
      - "Two Pertinent Questions": drafts, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1143)
      - "The Two Vampires of the Modern World," holograph, 1939 Jan 31 (Box 52, Folder 1144)
      - "Want a Scott Radio?"
        See: "Is a Scott Radio the Radio for You?", Box 52, folder 1132
      - Unidentified: drafts & publicity, 1931-35 (Box 52, Folder 1145)
    - Society of Friends
      - "Action and Reaction": outline (Box 52, Folder 1146)
      - "Are and Aren't": notes and typescripts (Box 52, Folder 1147)
      - "Authority, Inner and Outer": typescript (Box 52, Folder 1148)
      - "Belief in Others": holograph, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1149)
      - "Blessing and Curse": typescript (Box 52, Folder 1150)
      - "Buckingham": typescripts, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1151)
      - "Buckingham Friends School": typescript (Box 52, Folder 1152)
      - "A Call for Volunteers": outline, 1944 Mar 12 (Box 52, Folder 1153)
      - "Certain Quaker Practices": draft fragments, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1154-55)
      - "Chips": printed in Friends Intelligencer vol. 104, no. 52, 1947 Dec 27 (Box 52, Folder 1156)
      - "The Christian Witness in Society": outline, 1943 Mar 25 (Box 52, Folder 1157)
      - "Closing Session": typescript, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1158)
      - "Common and Uncommon": outline, 1943 Dec (Box 52, Folder 1159)
      - "Contact and Connectedness": outline, 1948 May 9 (Box 52, Folder 1160)
      - "Contributions of the Quakers": outline, 1949 Sep 26 (Box 52, Folder 1161)
      - "Counseling": notes, 1947 Sep 28 (Box 52, Folder 1162)
      - "The Creative Fountain": outline, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1163)
      - "Creative Purpose": outline, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1164)
      - "Creative Understanding": outlines, 1944 Jun 25 (Box 52, Folder 1165)
      - "The Crucial Struggle": outlines, 1939 Jan 10 (Box 52, Folder 1166)
      - "The Divine in Each of Us": outline, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1167)
      - "Do Friends Still Have a Peculiar, a Unique Message...?": outlines, 1945 Apr 1 (Box 52, Folder 1168)
      - "Does God Care for Man?": outline, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1169)
      - "Eight Points": outline, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1170)
      - "The Faith & Practice of the Friends": outlines, 1948-50 (Box 53, Folder 1171)
      - "Faith and Prayer": outlines, 1947 Sep-Dec (Box 53, Folder 1172)
      - "Farmers of Men": outline, 1943 Apr 18 (Box 53, Folder 1173)
      - "The Flavor of Man": outline, 1947 Apr 27 (Box 53, Folder 1174)
      - "The Flavor of Man": typescript & pamphlet, 1949 (Box 53, Folder 1175)
      - "For Work Camp Classes, Drew Seminary": outline, 1945 Jun 24-30 (Box 53, Folder 1176)
      - "Friends' Aims": Notes (Box 53, Folder 1177)
      - "Friends' Faith and Knowledge": outlines (Box 53, Folder 1178)
      - "The Friends of Being": drafts, 1940 Mar 10 (Box 53, Folder 1179)
      - "Friends of the Future": outline (Box 53, Folder 1180)
      - "Friends' Views": notes (Box 53, Folder 1181)
      - "Friends Worship": outlines, 1948 Apr 11 (Box 53, Folder 1182)
      - "George Fox": holograph, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1183)
      - "Holy Week": holograph, 1949 Apr 10 (Box 53, Folder 1184)
      - "How to Live -- What to Do": outline, 1944 Jul 7 (Box 53, Folder 1185)
      - "Human Beings": outlines, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1186)
      - "I Come to God": holograph, 1947 Oct 7 (Box 53, Folder 1187)
      - "The Ideal": outline, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1188)
      - "The Importance of Belief": outline, 1946 Jan 27 (Box 53, Folder 1189)
      - "The Importance of Decisions": outline, 1945 Jan 14 (Box 53, Folder 1190)
      - "The Importance of Growth": notes & holographs, 1946 May-Dec (Box 53, Folder 1191)
      - "The Inner Light": holograph, n.y. Oct 3 (Box 53, Folder 1192)
      - An Interpretation of Friends Worship": typescript (Box 53, Folder 1193)
      - "Is Good Will Possible to Men on Earth?": outline, 1945 Dec 23 (Box 53, Folder 1194)
      - "Keep the Inward Watch": typescript, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1195)
      - "Labor of Love": outline, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1196)
      - "Mankind in Emergency": outline, 1946 Oct 19 (Box 53, Folder 1197)
      - "Mankind is One": drafts, 1939 Jan-Feb (Box 53, Folder 1198-99)
      - "Mankind Means Brotherhood": notes & holographs, 1941 Mar 2 (Box 53, Folder 1200)
      - "Man's Part and God's": outline, 1943 Mar 13 (Box 53, Folder 1201)
      - "Message of Friendship": drafts and printed versions, 1944 (Box 53, Folder 1202)
      - "The Message of Quakerism": holographs, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1203-04)
      - "Method": drafts, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1205)
      - "Ministry and Counsel": typescript (Box 54, Folder 1206)
      - "Needs-Desires": outline, 1947 Jan 13 (Box 54, Folder 1207)
      - "One Form of Activity": typescript, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1208)
      - "The Other Invasion": typescripts, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1209)
      - "Our Continual Watch": outline, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1210)
      - "Overcoming the Fortress": draft, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1211)
      - "The Place of Struggle in the Religious Life": outlines, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1212)
      - "The Potent Reality": outline, 1948 Oct 3 (Box 54, Folder 1213)
      - "The Practice of the Presence": outline, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1214)
      - "Prayer": outline, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1215)
      - "Prayer": typescript, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1216)
      - "Prayer as Experience": holographs, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1217)
      - "Prayer, Meditation, Pondering, Worship": outline (Box 54, Folder 1218)
      - "The Presence of Love": typescript, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1219)
      - "The Psychological Approach": notes, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1220)
      - "Purchase Quarterly": outline, 1945 May 6 (Box 54, Folder 1221)
      - "Quakerism": holograph, 1944 Jul 7 (Box 54, Folder 1222)
      - "Quickening the Spiritual Forces": outline, 1940 Oct 11 (Box 54, Folder 1223)
      - "Religion and Our Common Ground": notes (Box 54, Folder 1224)
      - "Religious Experience": holograph, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1225)
      - "The Religious Life": outline & publicity, 1946 Jun (Box 54, Folder 1226)
      - "The Rise of Jesus and Ourselves": outline, 1950 Apr 9 (Box 54, Folder 1227)
      - "Santa Claus Will Not Bring Peace": notes and drafts, 1943 Nov-Dec (Box 54, Folder 1228)
      - "Scarcity and Abundance": outlines, 1948 Mar 21 (Box 54, Folder 1229)
      - "Seek Ye First": typescript, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1230)
      - Sermon: outline, 1949 Apr 17 (Box 54, Folder 1231)
      - "The Silent Meeting": outline, 1948 Oct 11 (Box 54, Folder 1232)
      - "The Skunk as an Example": notes, 1941 Nov (Box 54, Folder 1233)
      - "Social Service and Community Activities of Buckingham Friends Meeting": typescript, 1941 Dec 12 (Box 54, Folder 1234)
      - "Something More": typescript, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1235)
      - "The Spiritual Alternative to World War III"
        See: "Scarcity and Abundance", Box 54, folder 1229
      - "Talk to Young Friends at Gwynedd": outline, 1946 Nov 30 (Box 54, Folder 1236)
      - "These Three": typescript, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1237)
      - "This is Thy World": outline & draft, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1238)
      - "Those Who Grow": outline & draft, 1944 Jul 10, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1239)
      - "Three Humans": notes, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1240)
      - "Today May We Do It": typescripts, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1241)
      - "Transmission of the Torch": drafts, n.y. Nov 4 (Box 54, Folder 1242)
      - "The Uncommon Man": typescripts, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1243)
      - "Unfolding": typescripts, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1244)
      - "The Unseen Courage": outlines & publicity, 1942 Jul (Box 54, Folder 1245)
      - "The Way to Go": outline, drafts, & publicity, 1946-47 (Box 55, Folder 1246)
      - "What Are We Up Against?": notes, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1247)
      - "What Does It Profit Us?": outlines & publicity, 1941 Nov 23 (Box 55, Folder 1248)
      - "What Is Religion and What Is Its Function?": typescript, 1942 Jan 4 (Box 55, Folder 1249)
      - "What Quakerism Means to Us as Individuals": outline, 1945 Apr 21 (Box 55, Folder 1250)
      - "What to Stand For": outlines (Box 55, Folder 1251)
      - "Where Is Our Home?": outline, 1944 Jul (Box 55, Folder 1252)
      - "Why I Joined the Society of Friends": typescript (Box 55, Folder 1253)
      - "Why We Need God": outline, 1947 Oct 16 (Box 55, Folder 1254)
      - "Worship": outline, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1255)
      - "Worship and Love": typescript (Box 55, Folder 1256)
      - "Worship, Expected and Unexpected": outline, 1945 May 12 (Box 55, Folder 1257)
      - Unidentified: holograph fragments, 1942-50, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1258)
      - Unidentified: typescript fragments, 1942, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1259)
  - POETRY
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1260)
    - "Air" "And Pass" (Box 55, Folder 1261)
    - "Angelic Eve" "At Sea", n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1262)
    - Be With Me "Beehive", n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1263)
    - "The Blue Meridian", 1931-36 (Box 55, Folder 1264)
      See also: "Brown River Smile", Box 55, folder 1266
    - "The Blue Meridian and Other Poems": typescripts (Box 55, Folder 1265)
    - "Brown River Smile": typescript, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1266)
    - "Brown River Smile": printed in Pagany, vol. 3, no. 1 ( 2 copies), 1932 winter (Box 55, Folder 1267)
    - "But She Was", n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1268)
    - "A Certain Man", n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1269)
    - "Delivered at the Knighting of Lord Durgling" "Drift", n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1270)
    - "Earth" "The Earth and Us" "Equation", 1923 Jul 19, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1271)
    - "The Fable of a Creature" "Faint Drift", n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1272)
    - "Fire" "First Seal" "Five Vignettes", 1936 Apr 2, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1273)
    - "For Conscience" "For Union" "For Unity", 1939 Mar 6-15 (Box 55, Folder 1274)
    - "Georgia Dusk" "The Goose", n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1275)
    - "Gum": printed in The Chapbook, no. 36, 1923 Apr (Box 55, Folder 1276)
    - "Harvest Song": printed in The Double Dealer, vol. IV, no. 24, 1922 Dec (Box 56, Folder 1277)
    - "High Places" "Honey of Being" "How Many Lives?", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1278)
    - "I See Her Lovely There" "Imprint for Rio Grande" "It Used to Be" (Box 56, Folder 1279)
    - "Jazz Ode to the Intruders" "Jig and Ballard Entitled Morman and Suzanne" (Box 56, Folder 1280)
    - "Kitty Johnson", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1281)
    - "Let Us Go" "Like a Shark" Living Earth, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1282)
    - "The Lost Dancer" "Lucent Shield", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1283)
    - "Men" "Merl", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1284)
    - "Mill House Greetings": drafts & printed card, 1938 Nov-Dec (Box 56, Folder 1285)
    - "Motion and Rest" "My Knowing You" (Box 56, Folder 1286)
    - "Navarin": holograph of preface "Not Everyone Can Write Poems", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1287)
    - "November Cotton Flower": printed in The Nomad, vol. 2, no. 2, 1923 summer (Box 56, Folder 1288)
    - "One Note of Being"
      See: "Sing Yes", Box 56, folder 1295
    - "Only Emily", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1289)
    - "Poem in C", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1290)
    - "Prelude to Worship" "Preparation", 1939 Feb-Mar (Box 56, Folder 1291)
    - "Reflections": printed in The Dial, vol. LXXXVI, no. 4 (2 copies), 1929 Apr (Box 56, Folder 1292)
    - "Rolling, Rolling", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1293)
    - "Shaliol": book cover design, 1931 (Box 56, Folder 1294)
    - "Sing Yes" "Six Poems", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1295)
    - "Skyline" "Some Vague Opening", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1296)
    - "Song of the Son": printed in The Crisis, vol. 23, no. 6, 1922 Apr (Box 56, Folder 1297)
    - "Storm Ending": printed in The Double Dealer, vol. IV, no. 21, 1922 Sep (Box 56, Folder 1298)
    - "This Bone" "This He Taught Me", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1299)
    - "Three Poems", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1300)
    - "Tell Me" "Thanksgiving" "That I Am", 1922-38, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1301)
    - "To Gurdjieff Dying", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1302)
    - "Water", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1303)
    - "The Wayward and the Seeking" (Box 56, Folder 1304)
    - "What Dear?", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1305)
    - "White Arrow": typescripts, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1306)
    - "White Arrow": printed in The Dial, vol. LXXXVI, no. 7 (2 copies), 1929 Jul (Box 56, Folder 1307)
    - "Who Can Say" "Wolf From Lamb" "Words for a Hymn to the Sun", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1308)
    - Unidentified poems, 1938-51, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1309)
  - REVIEWS
    - Barton, Betsey. And Now to Live Again (Box 57, Folder 1310)
    - Bell, Bernard Iddings. A Man Can Live, 1947 (Box 57, Folder 1311)
    - Bright, John. Hizzoner Big Bill Thompson, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1312)
    - The Cloud of Unknowing, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 1313)
    - Colum, Padriac. Castle Conquer, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1314)
    - Drexelius, Jeremias. Heliotropium, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1315)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott. The Vegetable, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1316)
    - Frank, Waldo. Holiday, [1923?] (Box 57, Folder 1317)
    - Gale, Zona. Faint Perfume, [1923?] (Box 57, Folder 1318)
    - Gore, Charles. Prayer and the Lord's Prayer, 1947 (Box 57, Folder 1319)
    - Heard, Gerald. A Preface to Prayer, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1320)